<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isaac Lins on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Isaac Lins on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Daily Mac Software</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/my-daily-mac-drivers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/my-daily-mac-drivers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a Mac user (or even a Windows or Linux user) looking to get more shit done, you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly tweaking my setup for peak efficiency, and in the last few days, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided on a set of apps that I genuinely couldn&amp;rsquo;t live without. These are the tools that run daily, keeping my workflow smooth and upgrading to a poweruser.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are CTFs Pay2Win?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/skills-battle-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/skills-battle-2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s cut to the chase. The Skills Battle CTF. You know, that competitive shindig for us IT folks. My boss nudged me, said it&amp;rsquo;d be a &amp;ldquo;good idea.&amp;rdquo; So, I figured, why the hell not? Threw my hat in the ring, not expecting much.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-slow-burn-start&#34;&gt;The Slow Burn Start&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not gonna lie, I started out slower than a dial-up modem. Took me a painstaking &lt;strong&gt;45 minutes for a single flag&lt;/strong&gt;. I was all over the place, distracted. I needed to lock in, and fast. My position on the graph? Buried at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latest Post</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/latest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/latest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Redirecting you to the latest blog post&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cursor IDE: A Developer&#39;s Double-Edged Sword</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/cursor-ide-a-developers-double-edged-sword/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/cursor-ide-a-developers-double-edged-sword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Cursor IDE. If you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably heard of it. My journey with it? Well, it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a rollercoaster, a classic love-hate story.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-early-days-vs-code--copilot&#34;&gt;The Early Days: VS Code &amp;amp; Copilot&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I started my AI-assisted coding journey with Visual Studio Code and GitHub Copilot. My school hooked me up with a free license through their GitHub Pro program, which was sweet. Copilot was neat, definitely a step up from just having ChatGPT open in another window, but let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, it still felt a bit&amp;hellip; basic. It was helpful, but not a game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ghostty X Fish. The Perfect Combination</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/ghostty-fish-perfect-combo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/ghostty-fish-perfect-combo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me, always on the hunt for the perfect development environment, you know the thrill of finding tools that just &lt;em&gt;click&lt;/em&gt;. For a long time, I tweaked and prodded, swapped and searched. Then, I stumbled upon a combination so potent, so seamless, it didn&amp;rsquo;t just improve my workflow—it &lt;strong&gt;eradicated&lt;/strong&gt; everything that came before it. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Ghostty and Fish shell. Buckle up, because this is a game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My macOS Journey with an M3 MacBook</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/macos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took the plunge and bought a second-hand MacBook Pro M3. The price was a real head-turner – around 1200 CHF for a machine with only 6 battery cycles. It felt almost too good to be true! I&amp;rsquo;ve dedicated a good three days (and I&amp;rsquo;m still tinkering) to customizing it and getting a feel for the Apple ecosystem. Here are my initial impressions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-im-loving-so-far&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m Loving So Far&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s definitely a lot to be excited about with this new setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raycast. It&#39;s Hidden Power</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/raycast-its-hidden-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/raycast-its-hidden-power/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/images/svg/raycast.svg&#34; alt=&#34;raycast.svg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon Raycast even before I owned a Mac and instantly fell in love with the concept.&#xA;My friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/k3ntaw/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;@k3ntaw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (shoutout to him!) showed it to me, and I immediately started searching for Windows Application Launchers (I was mainly on Windows at the time).&#xA;My quest led me down a couple of paths:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-application-launcher&#34;&gt;What is an Application Launcher?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At its core, an application launcher is a tool designed to help you find and start applications on your computer with lightning speed. Think of it as a supercharged search bar for your entire system. Instead of clicking through folders or scrolling through menus, you simply type a few letters of what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for an app, a file, a command and the launcher brings it right up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model Context Protocol what now?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/mcp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You probably heard about MCP in the last few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you, it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing tool that&amp;rsquo;s shaking up the way AI systems connect with external data and tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-heck-is-mcp&#34;&gt;What the Heck is MCP?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;MCP stands for &lt;strong&gt;Model Context Protocol&lt;/strong&gt;. Here&amp;rsquo;s the simple version:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Purpose:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;MCP is an open standard that lets AI models (like our trusty assistants) interact with different data sources and systems without the messy custom integrations you&amp;rsquo;d normally need. Instead of writing a new connector for every tool and every model (an annoying M×N problem), MCP makes it one simple connection per tool.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
